（カカシ）あ～あ。
Oh boy...
お～い。
Hey...
サクラは　どこだ？
（キバ）え？　あぁ…。
Where's Sakura?
Huh? Oh...
サスケを追っていたんだろ？
You were going
after Sasuke, right?
サクラは　どっちに行ったの？
So which way did Sakura go?
北に向かって　２時の方向　１キロ…。
North... towards two o'clock.
About one kilometer.
ったく　サクラのヤツ→
That Sakura...
綱手様から
相当　強い薬の調合を教わったな。
Looks like she learned how to
concoct a powerful drug
from Lady Tsunade.
これじゃ　当分　起きないか。
They won't be getting up for a while.
よいしょっと。
There we go.
悪いが
時間がないんで先に行くよ。
Sorry, there's no time
so I'm going on ahead.
（サスケ）お前が俺についてきて
何の得がある？
What’s in it for me if
you come along?
何を企んでいる？
What are you plotting?
（サクラ）何も企んでなんかない。
I'm not plotting anything!
サスケ君が木ノ葉からいなくなって→
Ever since you left
the Hidden Leaf Village,
私は　あのとき
一緒に行かなかったことを→
I've regretted not going with you!
ずっと後悔してた。
《香燐：コイツ　昔の仲間か？
Is she an old teammate?
コイツもサスケを…。
And she’s also in love
with Sasuke? But...
だけど…》
サスケ君の望みどおりに動く。
I'll do whatever you want.
もう後悔したくない。
I don't want to have any more regrets.
俺の望みを知っているのか？
And do you know what I want?
そんなの何だっていい。
私は　サスケ君の言うとおりに…。
I don't care!
I'll do whatever you ask.
木ノ葉を潰す！
それが俺の望みだ。
I'm going to destroy the Hidden Leaf!
That's what I want!
お前は本当に　俺のために
木ノ葉を裏切れるのか？
Will you really be able betray
the Hidden Leaf for me?
うん　サスケ君が
そうしろと言うなら。
Yes. If you asked me to.
なら　それを証明してもらおう。
Then prove it.
コイツにトドメを刺せ。
Finish her off.
そうしたら　お前を認めてやる。
Then I'll believe you.
その人は？
Who is she?
俺の組織した鷹のメンバーだ。
A member of the group,
Taka, which I founded.
今は見てのとおり
使い物にならない。
As you can see, she's useless.
サクラ　お前は
医療忍者だったな。
Sakura, you're a Medical Ninja, right?
コイツの代わりになる。
ちょうどいい。
You can replace her.
This will work out just fine.
《こんなこと…。
How could he?
He's definitely not the old Sasuke.
やっぱり昔のサスケ君じゃない。
変わってしまった》
He's completely changed.
どうした　サクラ　できないのか？
Well, Sakura? You can’t do it?
《この人は関係ない。
She has nothing to do with this.
ここで私が　今　サスケ君を刺せば→
If I... If I stab Sasuke now...
すべてが終わる》
it will all be over.
やめろ　サスケ…。
Stop, Sasuke.
《本気の殺意》
He really meant to kill her.
落ちたな　サスケ。
How you’ve fallen, Sasuke.
ヘッ…　次から次へと。
One after another.
サクラ…　お前　ひとりで
サスケを殺そうとしただろう？
Sakura, you tried to kill Sasuke
by yourself, didn't you?
そんな重荷を
お前が背負うことはないんだよ。
You don't have to shoulder
such a heavy burden by yourself.
第７班の先生でありながら→
I was the leader of Team 7.
お前たちを
バラバラにさせてしまったのは→
It was my cowardice that
split all of you up.
俺の不甲斐なさだ。
サクラ　お前を安心させようと→
Sakura...
I said something irresponsible to you
無責任なことを言った。
in an effort to put you at ease.
((カカシ先生…。
Kakashi Sensei...
(大丈夫　また昔みたいになれるさ))
Don’t worry.
It will be like it was before!
自分自身に
言い聞かせていたのかもしれない。
I must have been trying to
convince myself of that too.
だらしない先生で　すまない。
I’m sorry I’m such
a careless Sensei.
そんなこと…。
But you’re...
サスケ…
俺は同じことを何度も言うのは→
Sasuke...
I don't like to
repeat myself.
あまり好きじゃない。
だが　もう一度だけ言っておく。
But I'll say this once more.
((お前のようなヤツは
腐るほど見てきたが→
I've seen so many guys
like you, I've lost count.
(復讐を口にしたヤツの末路は
ろくなもんじゃない))
Those who follow the path
of revenge end up nowhere.
復讐に　とりつかれるな。
Do not become possessed
by vengeance!
ククククッ…　ハッハッハッハッハッハ！
イタチを…　父を…　母を…。
Itachi... My father... My mother...
一族を　ここへ連れてこい！
My entire clan!
Bring them all here!
そうしたら
そんなものやめてやる。
Do that and I’ll quit right now!
お前を殺したくない。
I don't want to kill you.
俺を　いつでも殺せるみたいな
言いかただな。
You talk like you could kill me
at any time!
いつまでも
先生ヅラすんじゃねえよ。
Stop acting like
you’re still my Sensei.
俺は　アンタを殺したいと
うずうずしてるぜ。
I'm itching to kill you...
カカシ！
Kakashi.
《マダラに　ここまで…》
He’s been completely twisted
by Madara.
サクラ　その子を→
Sakura... Heal that girl to the point
that she can speak.
口が利ける程度まで
回復させてやれ。
今なら　まだ間に合う。
We still have time right now.
いろいろと
敵の情報を知ってる子だ。
She knows a lot of intel
about the enemy.
先生は？
What about you, Sensei?
お前は　その子を連れて
ここから離れてろ。
Take that girl and
get away from here.
《カカシ先生…》
Kakashi Sensei...
お前の覚悟の重さは
俺が受け取るよ。
I will take on what would
have been your burden.
まっ　これは俺の役目だ。
I guess you could say
it's my responsibility.
ほら！
All right?
早く行け　サクラ。
Hurry and go, Sakura.
第７班のリーダーとして→
As the leader of Team 7,
I will settle this once and for all.
すべての決着を　今ここでつける。
俺も同じことを
何度も言うつもりはない。
I don't like repeating myself either.
先生ヅラは　いいかげんやめろ。
But stop acting like
you’re my Sensei.
《どんなに落ちても→
No matter how far he had fallen,
大蛇丸が
かわいいと思えてたんだな。
he was still dear to you, wasn't he?
三代目　幾多の弟子を育ててきた
あなたでも→
Third Hokage...
Even though you had nurtured
many other fine pupils...
愛弟子が里を抜け→
A cherished student
abandons the village.
その愛弟子と
戦わねばならぬ　つらさ…。
The agony of having to face
that dear student in battle.
そして　他人には譲れぬ
その覚悟…》
No one can begin to imagine
the resolve it took.
三代目火影様が
どんな気持だったか→
Now I finally understand how
the Third Hokage must have felt.
今になって　わかるとはね。
アンタは　三代目の二の舞を
演じることになる。
You will go the same way
as the Third Hokage!
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo mamoru yo
I'll keep you safe even though I don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
tsuyogatte bakari de namida wa misenai
You act tough, and never show any tears
hontou wa kowai kuseni
But I know you're scared
taisetsu na mono wo ushinawa nu you ni
You keep running so you don't lose what's important
hisshi de hashirinukete kita
We've always survived through the long night
itsu datte nagai yoru wo futari de norikoeta
I'll always be by your side
kono mama issho ni iru kara
So you don't need to act tough
tsuyogatte naide ii nda yo
kimi wa ima namida nagashita
I can see the tears in your eyes,
nakijakuru kodomo no you ni
you're just like a crying child
tatoe asu ga mienaku natte mo susumu yo
We'll keep moving forward
even though we don't know what tomorrow will bring
natsu no sora miagete sakenda
I'll scream up to the summer sky
natsu no sora miagete niranda
I'll stare up to the summer sky
The Burden
お…　お前。
You...
今は　まだ　しゃべらないで
もう少しだから。
Don’t talk yet! Just a little longer.
《敵のお前の気持なんか
わかりたくもねえんだ。
You’re the enemy,
I don’t want to know how you feel.
だから　うちの前で→
So... stop crying in front of me...
そんな悲しい顔で
泣くんじゃねえよ。
with such a sad face!
ちくしょう…》
Damn it.
よし。
All right.
写輪眼ってのはな
うちはの証しだ。
The Sharingan is proof of
being an Uchiha.
うちは一族でもねえ
低俗な忍が→
A lowlife ninja who isn't an Uchiha...
その目を見せびらかすな！
has no right showing off that eye!
《手裏剣の射線上に…。
The path of those shuriken...
サスケめ　実戦慣れしてやがる。
Sasuke is used to real combat!
なら！》
Well then...
土遁　土流壁！
Earth Style: Mud Wall!
お前の写輪眼も　借り物にしちゃ
使い方がうまいほうだ。
For someone whose
Sharingan is borrowed,
you're quite skilled in using it.
だがな　キサマの写輪眼に
これができるか？
However, can your Sharingan do this?
俺とお前の写輪眼
その格の違いを教えてやる。
I will show you...
that my Sharingan is in
a completely different class than yours!
これは！
This is...
《速い！
万華鏡で消し飛ばさなければ→
So fast.
If I hadn't blown it away
with the Mangekyo,
やられていたな…》
I'd be dead right now.
それが　須佐能乎ってやつか。
So that's the Susano'o?
まさか　うちはでもないアンタが
万華鏡を開眼してるとはな。
To think that someone
who’s not an Uchiha
could awaken the Mangekyo.
助かったのは　どうやら
その眼の能力らしいが…。
So it seems that eye’s power
saved you.
うちはの力に感謝するんだな。
You should be grateful to
the power of the Uchiha.
サスケ　お前の中にあるのは
一族だけではないはずだ。
Sasuke...
You are more than just your clan.
More than just hatred.
憎しみだけじゃないはずだ。
もう一度　自分の心の奥底を
見つめてみろ。
Look deep inside your heart.
One more time.
まだ　そんなことを言ってんのか。
Are you still going on about that?
お前は　本当はわかってるはずだ。
Deep down, you know.
笑ってやがる。
You’re all laughing.
全員　笑ってやがる。
They're all laughing.
イタチの命と引き換えに
笑ってやがる！
You’re laughing at
the cost of Itachi’s life!
何も知らずに
一緒に　ヘラヘラ笑ってやがる！
Laughing together,
completely ignorant of everything!
今の俺にとって　お前らの笑い声は
軽蔑と嘲笑に聞こえる！
Your laughing voices
sound like contempt
and mocking to me now!
その笑いを
悲鳴と呻きに変えてやる！
I will change those laughs
to screams and wails!
《サスケ…》
Sasuke...
《サスケのチャクラが
更に冷たくなった》
Sasuke's chakra...
has gotten even colder.
サスケは　もう
お前の知っているサスケじゃない。
Sasuke isn't the Sasuke
you knew anymore.
こいつはまずい！
This is bad!
ハハハ…！
どうだ　こいつが　お前の借り物の
写輪眼で消せるか！？
How’s this?
So can your borrowed Sharingan
extinguish that?!
本物と借り物の差ってやつを
見せつけてやるぜ！
I will show you the difference
between the real thing and a fake!
クソッ！
Damn it!
《し…　視界が！》
My sight!
アイツ　何をする気だ？
What is she going to do?
《サクラ　何で出てきた！？》
Sakura! Why are you here?
よせ！
Don’t!
《カカシ先生に
重荷は背負わせない！》
I won't let Kakashi Sensei
bear the burden!
((俺たちの決定を
アイツが　ナルトが素直に聞くかね？
Do you think Naruto will
calmly accept our decision?
（リー）けど　それが
僕たちの総意ですから→
But this is something
we all decided.
なんとしても
わかってもらわないと。
We have to make him understand.
ナルトには　すべて私から話す。
サクラさんが？
I'll talk to Naruto about everything.
何か名案でもあんのか？
You, Sakura?
Do you have a plan that'll work?
とにかく　私に任せて。
Just leave everything to me.
《こんなこと…
ナルトに言えるわけない。
How can I tell Naruto
something like this?!
私が　全部うまくやんなきゃ。
覚悟を決めなきゃ》
I have to take care of this.
I have to stay committed.
ちょっと
そこの席　通してくれる？
Hey!
Can you let me through?
ナルト　どけ！　私は
アンタの向こう側に座りたいのよ！
Get outta the way, Naruto!
I want to sit over there.
サスケ君　隣　いい？
Sasuke...
Mind if I sit next to you?
《今日こそ　サスケ君を
ゲットしてやるわ！
I'm going to get Sasuke today!
ファーストキスは　私が奪うのよ！
しゃ～んなろ～っ！》
I’ll be the one to get
the first kiss! Shannaro!
お前ら　最後に
もう一度だけチャンスをやる。
I'll give you guys
one more chance!
ただし　昼からは
もっと過酷な鈴とり合戦だ。
However, after noon it'll be
a harsher battle to take the bells!
挑戦したいヤツだけ
弁当を食え。
Those who want to take
on the challenge can eat lunch.
ただし　ナルトには食わせるな。
However, don't let Naruto have any.
ルールを破って
１人昼飯を食おうとした罰だ。
It's punishment for breaking
the rules and
attempting to eat lunch
on your own.
もし食わせたりしたら→
If someone lets him eat
ソイツをその時点で
試験失格にする。
that person will be disqualified
on the spot.
ここでは　俺がルールだ。
I make the rules here.
わかったな。
Got it?!
ほらよ。
あっ　ちょ…。
Here.
ちょっと　サスケ君
さっき先生が…。
H-Hey, Sasuke.
Sensei just said...
大丈夫だ　今アイツの気配はない。
It's okay.
There's no sign of him now.
昼からは
３人で鈴をとりにいく。
In the afternoon, the three of us
will go and get the bells.
足手まといになられちゃ
こっちが困るからな。
It'll be trouble for me if
he becomes a hindrance, so...
サスケ君。
Sasuke...
（ナルト）え！？　サクラちゃん？
Sakura...
ヘヘヘッ　ありがとう。
Thanks.
お前ら！
You guys!
どわ～！
キャー！
合格！
You pass!
お前らが　初めてだ。
You guys are the first.
今までのヤツらは　素直に
俺の言うことを聞くだけの→
Up until now,
I only had dunces
ボンクラばかりだったからな。
who would just meekly listen
to what I said.
忍は裏の裏を読むべし。
A ninja must see
through deception.
忍の世界で　ルールや掟を破るヤツは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
In the ninja world, those who
break the rules are scum.
けどな　仲間を大切にしないヤツは
それ以上のクズだ。
But those who abandon
their friends are worse than scum.
これにて　演習終わり！
全員集合！
That's it for the exercise.
Everyone passes.
夜中に　こんなところで
何うろついている？
Why are you hanging around
a place like this
in the middle of the night?
里を出るには
この道を通るから→
It’s because you use this path
to leave the Village.
いつも　ここに…。
I always...
帰って寝てろ。
Go home and sleep.
どうして
何も言ってくれないの？
Why won’t you tell me anything?
なんで　いつも黙って
私に何一つ話してくれない…。
Why are you always silent?
You won’t tell me one single thing.
余計なお世話だって
言ってんだよ。
I’m telling you to keep
your nose out of my business.
いちいち俺に構うな。
Stop fussing over everything I do.
私って　サスケ君に
嫌われてばっかりだね。
I always...
end up making
you hate me, don’t I?
覚えてる？
Do you remember?
下忍になって　初めて
スリーマンセルのチームが決まった日→
We just made genin and
the three-man squads were assigned.
その場所で　初めてサスケ君と
２人っきりになったとき→
You and I were alone
for the first time,
here in this very spot.
私を　怒ったわね。
You got mad at me.
孤独…。
Solitude...
え？
It isn’t the same as being sad
親に叱られて
悲しいなんてレベルじゃねえぞ。
because your parents
scolded you.
どうしたの？　急に。
What’s the matter all
of a sudden?
お前　うざいよ！
You... are annoying.
覚えてないな。
I don’t remember that.
そうだよね
もう　ずいぶん前のことだもんね。
Yeah, I guess.
That was long ago after all.
でも　あの日から始まったんだよ。
But it all began that day.
サスケ君と私。
You and me...
そして　ナルトに　カカシ先生。
And also Naruto and
Kakashi Sensei.
４人で　いろんな任務やって→
The four of us went on
various missions.
苦しかったし　いろいろ
大変だったけど→
Those were tough and
difficult times, but...
でも　やっぱり何より
楽しかった。
But more than anything,
it was so much fun.
サスケ君の一族のことは知ってる。
I know about your clan, Sasuke.
でも　復讐だけなんて
誰も幸せになんてなれない！
But revenge that won’t bring
anyone happiness. No one.
サスケ君も私も。
Neither you nor I.
やっぱりな…。
As I expected.
俺は　お前たちとは違う。
I’m different
from you guys.
お前たちとは
相容れない道にいる。
I’m walking a road that’s incompatible
with the rest of you.
４人でやってきた。
The four of us worked together...
確かに　それを自分の道と
思おうとしたこともある。
and it’s true that there was
a time when I thought that was my road.
４人でやってきたが
俺の心は　結局　復讐を決めた。
The four of us worked together,
but in the end,
I decided on revenge.
俺は　そのために生きてきた。
That’s been my reason for living.
俺は　お前や
ナルトのようにはなれない！
I can’t be like you or Naruto.
また　サスケ君は
自ら孤独になるの？
Are you going to isolate
yourself again, Sasuke?!
サスケ君は　あのとき
孤独はつらいって教えてくれた。
Back then, you taught me
that solitude is suffering, Sasuke.
今は　それが　痛いほどわかる。
Now I know exactly how that feels.
私には　家族も友達もいる。
I have both family and friends.
だけど　サスケ君がいなくなったら→
But if you were
no longer here, Sasuke...
私には…
私にとっては孤独と同じ。
for me it would be the same
as solitude.
また　ここから　それぞれ
新しい道が始まるだけ。
From here...
we’re going to start walking down
our new paths individually.
私は！　私は　サスケ君が
好きで好きで　たまらない！
I... I love you so
very, very much, Sasuke!
サスケ君が　私と一緒にいてくれれば
絶対　後悔させない！
If you would only be
with me, Sasuke,
I wouldn't let you regret it,
no matter what!
私　サスケ君のためなら
なんだってする！
I’ll do anything for you, Sasuke!
だから
お願いだからここにいて！
So... I’m begging you,
please stay here!
復讐だって手伝う！
I’ll even help you
with your revenge!
絶対　私が
なんとかしてみせるから！
I’ll make it happen somehow,
I promise you!
だから　ここに…。
So stay here with me!
私と一緒に…。
それが　ダメなら
私も一緒に連れてって。
If that doesn’t work for you,
then take me with you.
やっぱり　お前　うざいよ。
You really are... annoying.
行かないで！
Don't go!
行くなら　私
大声出してでも…。
If you go, I'll scream and...
サクラ…。
Sakura...
(ありがとう))
Thank you.
《覚悟したはずなのに…》
I was sure... I was prepared.
サクラ！
Sakura!
《クソッ！万華鏡を使ったら
すぐこれだ！》
Damn it!
This always happens right after
I use the Mangekyo!
うっ！
よせ！　サスケ！
Stop, Sasuke!
《ナルト！》
Naruto?!
ナルト！
Naruto...
te ashi tsunagareteru yo i'm like marionetto
My hands and feet are tied up, I'm Like a marionette
sonna no arienee yo ittai dounatteru yo
This is nonsense, What's going on?
tell me tell me who's the ruler? kiyasuku sawaruna
(Tell Me Tell Me) Who's the Ruler?
Don't put your hands on me
kikitakuneeyo mou kiben wa
I don't want to hear your false arguments anymore
kokkara sakiwa ore ga kimen da!
I'm in charge of my own life from now on
mienai kusari wo tachikire
Break the invisible chains
genkai sure sure dashikire
Test your limits
jibun de kachi toranakya
If you don't win it for yourself
darekano te ni watacchauze
Someone else will take it
stand up! saa mina reach out for liberty
Stand Up!! C'mon everybody Reach Out For Liberty
ima ga ugokidasu toki da
It's time to make a move
wake up! saa mina step up shite sakebe
Wake Up!! C'mon everybody Step Up and shout
oh yes we are the dreamer
run for your freedom
saki datsu mono nante nakutatte
Even though you don't have a reason
run for your freedom
yume no tobira kettobashite
Kick the door to your dream
so you better stand up!! saa mina reach out for liberty
(so you better) Stand Up!!
C'mon everybody Reach Out For Liberty
ima ga ugokidasu toki da
It's time to make a move
wake up! saa mina step up shite sakebe
Wake Up!! C'mon everybody Step Up and shout
oh yes we are the dreamer
run for your freedom
saki datsumono nante nakutatte
Even though you don't have a reason
run for your freedom
yume no tobira ketto bashite
Kick the door to your dream
fight for your freedom
（くもじい）
もしもし　そこのあなた。
Next Episode
Sasuke, I’m going to save you from the chaos of your vengeance.
たまには　空から日本を
眺めてみるというのは→
どうじゃろう？
今回は　埼京線の上を
飛んでいくぞ。
I don’t need that.
The stage has already been set for my vengeance to happen!
（くもみ）ということは
埼玉県にも突入ですね。
What?
そうじゃ。　この沿線には
不思議な景色はもちろん→
Severing all bonds with the Leaf
shall lead to the Uchiha’s true restoration!
小さな巨人ともいえる→
シェアＮｏ．１工場が たくさん　ひそんどるぞ。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Two Fates"
Two Fates
なんですか？　これ。
I guess we just have to do this then.
では　そろそろ出発じゃ。